Guide to the Charles Cecil Wyche Papers, 1902-1963 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Charles Cecil Wyche papers 1902-1963 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Wyche, Charles Cecil, 1885-
13 linear feet Extent: 9,736 Items
Lawyer and U.S. District Judge, of Spartanburg, S.C. Personal, political, and professional letters and papers relating to Wyche's personal life, his early legal practice, social life and customs in South Carolina, local politics in South Carolina, his term in Congress (1913-1914), his service in World War I, the political career of Cole L. Blease, Wyche's interest in reform, and the 1924 senatorial election in South Carolina.
RL.02072
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Charles Cecil Wyche Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1954.
Collection Overview
Papers of Charles Cecil Wyche, lawyer and United States district judge for the western district of South Carolina, contain correspondence and papers concerning business and legal affairs, politics, and family matters. Specific topics include Wyche's support of John Gary Evans in his campaign to be United States senator from South Carolina, 1908; descriptions of Paris, Brussels, and Berlin in letters of Isoline Wyche, 1909-1910; an attempt to prevent the granting of a pardon by Governor Cole L. Blease of South Carolina, 1911; Wyche's term in the state legislature, 1913; Wyche's legal business, particularly relating to the collection of debts and suits for damages in cases of industrial and automobile accidents; the campaign of Cole L. Blease for the governorship of South Carolina, 1916; attempts by Wyche to form a regiment of volunteers for service in Mexico or Europe; the influenza epidemic of 1920; and the national and state election of 1924, especially Wyche's support for James F. Byrnes in his race for the United States Senate against Nathaniel Barksdale Dial.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Blease, Coleman Livingston, 1868-1942; Lawyers -- Correspondence; Lawyers -- Political activity; Lawyers -- South Carolina; Legislators -- South Carolina; Governors -- South Carolina; South Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; South Carolina -- Social life and customs
Contents of Collection
- Professional and Personal Papers Series, 1902-1924 and undated, (11 boxes)
  - 1902-1911 July (Box 1)
  - 1911 Aug.-1914 (Box 2)
  - 1915 Jan.-1916 Feb. (Box 3)
  - 1916 Mar.-1917 Apr. 14 (Box 4)
  - 1917 Apr. 15-1920 Aug. (Box 5)
  - 1920 Sept.-1921 Aug. (Box 6)
  - 1921 Sept.-1922 Sept. (Box 7)
  - 1922 Oct.-1923 June (Box 8)
  - 1923 July-1924 Mar. (Box 9)
  - 1924 Apr.-Dec. (Box 10)
  - Undated (Box 11)
- Correspondence Series, 1932-1963, (10 boxes)
  - 1932-1938 Feb. (Box 12)
  - 1938 Mar.-1939 Oct. (Box 13)
  - 1939 Nov.-1941 Aug. (Box 14)
  - 1941 Sept.-1950 Feb. (Box 15)
  - 1950 Mar.-1951 Dec. (Box 16)
  - 1952 Jan.-1953 Oct. (Box 17)
  - 1953 Nov.-1955 Mar. (Box 18)
  - 1955 Apr.-1956 Dec. (Box 19)
  - 1957 Jan.-1959 Mar. (Box 20)
  - 1959 Apr.-1963 (Box 21)
- Clippings Series, (1 box)
  - Clippings (Box 22)
- Financial Papers Series, (1 box)
  - Financial papers (Box 22)
- Invitations Series, (1 box)
  - Invitations (Box 22)